The Bogucki Family papers 1936-2009 CPAA 05-05
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
The Bogucki Family papers
1936-2009
Jadwiga K. Bogucki; Alfred S. Bogucki
CPAA 86-02
6 boxes (5.5 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
Mr. and Mrs. Bogucki lived in Philidelphia, PA. They were both educated and very active in many Polish American organizations on the state and national level. In addition to organizing and participating in many events, they supported worthy endeavors related to Polish history, culture, and language.
Historical/Biographical Note
Mr. Alfred S. Bogucki and Mrs. Jadwiga Kulpinski Bogucki were very active in Polish American organizations in the Philadelphia area. Mr. Alfred S. Bogucki, son of Ignacy and Martha Bogucki was born on Dec. 27, 1914. He graduated in 1943 from Temple University with medical degree. Mr. Bogucki served in the U.S. army as a physician and from 1949-1976 he worked for the City of Philadelphia Department of Public Health. He died on Dec. 27, 1980.
Mrs. Jadwiga Kulpinska Bogucki, daughter of Piotr and Florentyna Kulpinski, was born on Oct. 13, 1915 in Philadelphia. Four years later the family returned to Poland for several years and in 1926 returned to Philadelphia and opened the Richmond Bakery. Jadwiga was educated at the Drexel Institute of Technology and received her Masters degree in Home Economics. She then went into teaching at college and high school level. While at Drexel she joined Polish Intercollegiate Club (PKM) and learned to play tennis. Jadwiga became the first PKM tennis tournament champion in 1936. She was active in the club for several decades and held various positions. After marrying Alfred, she became a housewife and together with her husband was very active in many Polish-American organizations in the Philadelphia area. Mr. and Mrs. Bogucki have one son Peter, who was born on March 11, 1954. Mrs. Bogucki's special interest was in education, Polish culture and language. She was tireless advocate of keeping Polish heritage alive and this translated into cultivating Polish traditions and language. The Boguckis organized events and participated in the Polish People's University, Paderewski Choral Society, Pulaski Day Parade, Kosciuszko Foundation, and the Polish American Historical Association. Mr. and Mrs. Bogucki were deeply religious and were among the initial group of volunteers who helped to establish the National Shrine of Czestochowa in Doylestown, PA. Mrs. Jadwiga Bogucki died on July 19, 2009.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Collection consists of personal and organizational correspondence, anniversary booklets, and pamphlets. Since the Boguckis' actively participated in activities of many organizations, their papers include broad documentation of activities of organizations such as, Polish Intercollegiate Club (PKM), Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia, Polish People's University, Polish American Historical Association, and several others. There is also a large amount of news clippings from various events in the Philadelphia area from the 1930's till late 1990's. Mrs. Bogucki was interested in preservation and teaching of the Polish language, therefore the collection has many pamphlets and publication related to language instruction.
The collection is open for research.
Two donations were made by Peter Bogucki son of Jadwiga and Alfred Bogucki in 2005, and third part of materials was donated after Mrs. Bogucki death in December of 2009.
Search Terms
Jadwiga K. Bogucki; Alfred S. Bogucki; Polish Intercollegiate Club.; Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia -- Periodicals.; Catholic Church -- Pennsylvania -- Doylestown.; Polish Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Periodicals.; Polish Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia --Periodicals.; Polish Americans -- Pennsylvania.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Clippings.
Related Material
For related material see the following collections:
Amarican Council for Polish Culture records CPAA 96-03
Arrangement
Material in the collection is arranged by date and by organization.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Jadwiga and Alfred Bogucki biography., 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jadwiga Bogucki eulogy by her son Peter Bogucki., July 23, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jadwiga Bogucki correspondence., 1962-2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Jadwiga Bogucki membership in professional organization., 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jadwiga Bogucki membership lists from various Polish American organizations in Philadelphia area., 1953-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Jadwiga Bogucki, Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - correspondence., 1980-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - clippings., 1969-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy 50th Anniversary and 70th Anniversary., 1968, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy, lectures., 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - financial information and related correspondence., 1970-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - correspondence., 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy program odczytow., 1975-2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy in Philadelphia - 75th Anniversary., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - membership., 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - Jadwiga Bogucka's letter of resignation from PUL board - letters and related material., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Polski Uniwersytet Ludowy - correspondence with Rev. Roman Nir about PUL archives., 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15A)
- Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia - constitution draft and final version. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia officers., 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia - correspondence and announcements, pt.1., 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Polish Heritage Society of Philadelphia - correspondence and announcements, pt.2., 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Polish Heritage Society/Paderewski Choral Society - clippings, flyers., 1980's (Box 1, Folder 20)
- PKM Polskie Kolo Miedzykolegilne - Polish Intercollegiate Club, constitution., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club - photogrpahs from various activities of the club., 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club - event booklets for Polish Night Out and Graduate Ball., 1937-1986, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club - correspondence, announcements (scattered issues)., 1970-1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club - clippings., 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club, correspondence, announcements., 1939-1963, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club, report of the Clubhouse Investigation Committee., March, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club, social events and lectures announcements., 1937, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Polish Intercollegiate Club, membership and committees lists. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Philadelphia Professional Society, membership lists., [undated] (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Philadelphia Professional Society, correspondence and minutes., 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Philadelphia Professional Society, cultural events., 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Philadelphia Professional society, list of members., [undated] (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Associated Polish Home, financial reports., 1908-1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Associated Polish Home, correspondence, newsletter, flyers., 1965-1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Associated Polish Home, Articles of Association., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Polish University Club of New Jersey., 1946, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "The Yowler" monthly bulletin of St. John Cantius Catholic Club., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "Loafers Newsletter" a bulletin, Chicopee, MA., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Polish American Historical Association (PAHA) - Roaster., 1966-1967, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- PAHA - Constitution and standing rules with amendments., 1964, 1971, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- PAHA - membership and subscriber lists., 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- PAHA - report of the executive board and related correspondence., 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- PAHA - membership, dues, financial information., 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- PAHA - reports of Jadwiga Bogucka, the chapter coordinator., 1974, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- PAHA - Jadwiga Bogucka's Appeal for chapter organizers and membership chairmens., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- PAHA Jadwiga Bogucka's essay "PAHA Chapters: the first decade., 1965-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7A)
- PAHA - correspondence, minutes, agendas., 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- PAHA - correspondence, minutes., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- PAHA - correspondence, minutes., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- PAHA - correspondence, minutes., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- PAHA - correspondence., 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- PAHA - brochures, programs, clippings., 1966-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- PAC Eastern Pennsylvania - correspondence, announcements, minutes., 1963-1987, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- PAC Eastern Pennsylvania - invitations to cultural events, flyers., 19 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- PAC Eastern Pennsylvania - membership lists from Gwiazda newspaper., 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- PAC Eastern Pennsylvania - by-laws., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Polish Army Veterans Association, Philadelphia chapter - correspondence., 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Adam Mickiewicz Polish Language School - 50th Anniversary and announcements of events., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC) - letters, announcements, flyers., 1965-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Polish Beneficial Association - clippings, pamphlets., 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The National Shrine of Our Lady of Czestochowa at Doylestown - Mr. and Mrs. Bogucki voluntary work and related correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- The National Shrine of Our Lady of Czestochowa at Doylestown - fundraising efforts, invitations, letters, brochures., 1966-1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- The National Shrine of Our Lady of Czestochowa at Doylestown - press clippings related to financial controversy., 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- The National Shrine of Our Lady of Czestochowa at Doylestown - various pamphlets., various dates (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Polish parrishes in Pennsylvania - pamphlets, letters, clippings., 1974-1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Polish parrisnes and clergy in diocese of New York, Pennsylvania, Connecticut, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, Maine, New Jersey., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- John Cardinal Krol of Philadelphia - In Memoriam booklet, press clippings., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- John Cardinal Krol of Philadelphia - articles and interviews., 1980's (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Polish Artistic Programs organized by Henryk Michalski., 1970-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Polish Artistic Programs organized by Jan Wojewodka., 1966-1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- The constitution of the Association for the Advancement of Polish Studies and related material., 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Students essays on Polish immigrants in Delaware and Philadelphia., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Letters of Rev. John A. Klekotka written by Sister Laurencita while traveling through the Orient., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- 2 essays on Polonia: "Walter Ossowski's contribution to Polonia" and memorial service for Zygmunt A. Piotrowski., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- ., 19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Poland's Millennium celebration in the US and Philadlephia, various brochures, programs, clippings., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "The Polish Millenium" essay by Eugene Kusielewicz., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Kongres Wspolczesnej Nauki I Kultury Polskiej na Obczyznie, program, clippings., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- National medical and Dental association of America - Alfred Bogucki's membership., 1960's (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Nicolaus Copernicus celebration in Phildaelphia, pamphlets, clippings., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Nicolaus Copernicus celebration in Phildaelphia, promotional items., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Philadelphia Museum of Art, membership, correspondence, programs., 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Philadelphia Museum of Art - Art Treasures from Poland exhibit, clippings., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Philadelphia Museum of Art - Art Treasures from Poland exhibit - catalog, related correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- AMPOL - American of Polish Descent Cultural Society, membership list, cultural events. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Paderewski Foundation, NYC - pamphlets., 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Piosenki i Nuty Choru Filadelfijskiego., 1960's (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Polish Dramatic at the Polish National Home in Philadelphia "Niespodzianka"., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Nazareth Academy, pamphlets and related material., 1960's (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Holy Family College, pamphlets, constitution, newsletters., 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- St. Adalbert and St. Ladislaus Church - parishes of Mr. and Mrs. Bogucki., 1980's (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Our Lady of Calvary Parrish in Philadelphia, letters, bulletins, announcements., 1959-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Polski Instytut Teatralny i Nina Polan, brochures, clippings., 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Polish Museum of America, brochures, letters., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Kosciuszko Foundation, invitations, social events, clippings., 1960-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences in America (PIASA), brochures, letters., 1970-2003 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Pilsudski Institute of America, events, letters, clippings., 1968-1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- American Relief for Poland, correspondence., 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Constitutions of Polish American organizations: The Society of volunteers of Our Lady of Czestochowa; Kosciuszko Foundation chapters; The Philadelphia Professional Club; Friends of the Holy Family College, PAHA California Chapter, Men of Nazareth. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Polish customs - handwritten notes by Jadwiga Bogucki. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Philadelphia folklife resources includes information on Polish folklore., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- "Polish legends" by Lena Tytek Piotrowska., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Jan Karski - biography, clippings. (Box 3, Folder 28)
- "Progressives, socialists and the Milwaukee Poles" essay by Donald E. Pienkos., [1975?] (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Alliance College - pamphlets, course descriptions, press clippings related to closing of the college., 1965-1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Alliance College - Kujawiaki dance group, photographs, programs, announcements., 1960's-1970's (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Newspaper clippings from Polish American and American press related to Polish issues., 1965-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Pamphlet, brochures, announcements and press clippings related to Polish and Polish American issues., 1962-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Various publications related to the Polish language, culture and religion., 1960-1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)